ELIUD NGORONGO

KENYAN | 23 00614 | +254721503505

eliudnjenga@gmail.com| LinkedIn Profile| My Portfolio

SUMMARY

I am deeply passionate about technology and the impact it can have on the supply chain industry. This is largely due to my experience in operations. I enjoy networking and finding ways to collaborate with others on projects - an aspect that I believe both coding and technology are capable of achieving as they connect people to one another.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Holberton - ALX– Nairobi, Kenya Certificate in Software Engineering

May, 2021 - May, 2022

Google Andela Dev Scholarship – Nairobi, Kenya

October, 2021 – February, 2022

Certificate in Cloud Engineering

The University of Nairobi – Nairobi, Kenya

September, 2012 – May, 2016

Bsc. Actuarial Science

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Generation Agent (remote)

Ontop - Delaware, USA

November, 2021 - Present

- Developed 200 sales leads per week through cold calling, marketing lists, and internet leads.
- Working in SalesForce and Apollo CRM and identified 55 decision-maker contacts, collected qualifying information, and coordinated and set appointments for sales staff.

Operations Team Member(part time)

June, 2019 – Present

Pemarcress -Nairobi, Kenya

- Optimised internal processes and streamlined business functionality that resulted in a 48% expense decrease by the second year.
- Lead in partnership with Safaricom to introduce Bill Manager for a well-curated rent collection system.

Operation Team Lead

Marina Stores - Nairobi, Kenya

January, 2018 - Present

- Installation, implementation, and maintenance of the Sage 50 ERP system and also trained my team to use it. This has greatly reduced redundancies as well as grown the customer base. The debt owed to the business was reduced by 39% in the first year.
- Identify customer needs and preferences using reports generated by the Sage 50 ERP system. This helps the business identify its best and lowest performing products and adjust accordingly.
- Responsible for leading the sales, supply, and manufacturing teams with a total of 18 people.

SKILLS

• Logistics

Python

• SQL

• Leadership

• C

• Shell scripting

• Commercial Awareness

• HTML/CSS

Javascript

INTERESTS

• Supply chain

Culinary

Gaming

LANGUAGES

English - ExpertSwahili - Native

Kikuyu - ExpertFrench - Beginner

• German - Beginner

PROJECTS

• Printf – Prints output to display.

•Shell – Linux CMD

●HbnB – AirBNB Clone